hey everyone thanks for listening to the
grow your life podcast my name is
jeremiah krakowski and if we haven't met
yet i help course creators coaches
trainers authors mentors speakers get
more
clients
make more revenue and reach more people
with their message
and so if you're a coach trainer author
speaker mentor even minister like the
man that i'm about to bring up here i'm
going to introduce you to
this podcast is for you to help you grow
your vision to reach higher levels and
to break past what's stopping you from
getting there now today i have the honor
and privilege of having jason
phillips he is a father international
speaker follower of jesus
he runs a ministry called revival town
ministries he started a number of
businesses he's a humanitarian that
believes in in giving back and taking
care of people and getting deeply
involved in in communities help me
welcome jason phillips how are you doing
jason hey good jeremiah doing great
thanks for having me on today appreciate
it yeah
you're you're quite the quite the
pioneer in your
space in a lot of the stuff that you're
doing i think that that best describes
you
it's awesome how did you get started
in
doing
uh what you're doing now how did you get
started um
i guess a mystery in business tell tell
me a little bit about that story
yeah uh so in in ministry i uh i always
knew that uh there was a calling or
something on my life to uh to be a risk
taker and and and see massive change
happen and so
i got involved when i was 23 with an
organization called youth with a mission
ywam and i went for three months uh to
admissions training center and then i
spent three months in india and i was 23
years old and the first time it was the
first time i'd actually traveled outside
of the u.s and
you know i got to go to mother teresa's
home and and just saw
amazing things but at the same time you
know i was broken over over the needs of
the planet and so
uh during the next five years um
we started uh several ministries we
raised forty thousand dollars and built
a church and an orphanage in india one
of the places that we've been to
and we just started to uh really spread
awareness about uh
the needs of the planet and you know i
began to speak and teach and and you
know that but that was the very first
place that that i got impacted at you
know 23 years old and and now this
october it'll be um 25 years since that
that happened and wow um so it was it
was several encounters really that
happened to me that that just kind of
launched us
into going to the nations as well as
you know just sharing about um the
kingdom of god and everything it was
just a real powerful time
what um when you talk about the needs of
the planet what would what would those
be like that really
pulled you because like
what impacted you that yeah the needs of
it yeah
just just things we take for granted
here as far as clean water
um you know food and things like that
you know there's billions of people that
don't have access to clean water there's
uh people who have access to uh proper
sanitation
and so that that was things that you
know basic needs that people had that
weren't being met and so
uh that was one of the reasons why uh
when you asked about business uh we
started i started two businesses i
started a juice bar and we had a
one-for-one program uh for a long time
so every time somebody bought a juice
we would provide uh a meal for somebody
in a in a developing country it's like a
one-for-one kind of similar to what tom
shoes has done
and then the same thing we started a a
water bottle company and we were doing
the same thing uh with that as well i i
should have had you send me a water
bottle before we yeah start
yeah sure we'll pretend like it is
sure
yeah so so basically
i had
a lot of time in full-time ministry and
then i transitioned into business and
but my heart has always been uh to give
back and that you know whatever you're
doing in life whether it's business or
ministry or you're just starting a
business right now and you're thinking
about you know getting your business
going one of the things that i always
feel is that when you get your vision
beyond
your current need then god begins to
pour back into your vision and into the
things that you're on so i always i
always didn't want the business just to
be like let's make revenue but how can
we change the planet how can we make a
positive impact um whether it's just
giving somebody a meal or
clean water you know and so i was using
that give back system as far as you know
in in business
awesome
i want to to ask you about that is
when people have a vision a lot of the
people who especially listen to this
podcast they have an idea of what they
want to do they have an idea where they
want to go but it's risky and you you
are a man that knows about taking risk
what would you say to people that are
just like it's too
risky
for me to go after the vision that i
have
yeah i mean that's a really good
question and
a lot of what i've done
on the outside people you know might see
confidence but it's it's really it's
fear and trembling and so
one of the things i say if if there's
something burning inside of you and you
know you need to do it
number one do it afraid uh you're
probably gonna have some fear you're
probably gonna have some doubt but you
need to
let the vision that's burning inside of
you propel you to do something that will
get you beyond that that fear and so
i've taken a lot of risks when i started
our juice bar it was called zoe juice
bar you can look it up now it's still in
business and i was actually able to sell
the thing after after six years and it's
it's still operating and they've got a
great team but i risked everything i had
you know wife a mortgage and i quit my
job i had loans and and uh i was full of
anxiety because i stepped into something
i had never done before
um but the other thing that i that i
realized is is and i know you talk about
this a lot jeremiah is that is that you
need to be willing to ask for help and
if you don't know something
somebody knows it somewhere and you can
find out and so
i wasn't the guy that uh
you know there's nothing new under the
sun so there's juice bars all over the
place and i just found some places in
california that were doing it well and i
thought well what kind of spin can we do
on it but then i started getting
business coaches
in the local area that would help us
with our profit and loss and and pricing
our products and things like that and so
yeah basically really quickly um i
figured out what i didn't know
and then i uh i just kept going forward
and i made
a lot of mistakes
uh especially in the beginning i had our
products priced too low i had employees
that um i should have had working for me
in the beginning and and all different
things and and then i learned a lot
about systems too um you know that i
need to create systems in the business
and so
uh but back to their original question
you know if if somebody's watching today
and you're afraid to step out you know
find somebody that's doing uh what you
want to do and and ask questions and
find a coach or a mentor yeah or you
that can can really guide you because
uh one one thing that happened that was
so so crazy is i was meeting with a
business coach of mine a local one
and he's like jason you have a lot of
revenue coming in but you have this much
profit i'm like yeah i know that that's
why i'm with you man i'm stressed out
and he said uh
he said have you thought about raising
your price 50 cents
i'm a man of action and so i i mean i
was a little bit nervous you don't you
know like okay why are you raising your
price but literally
three days later our price was raised by
50 cents almost no customers thought
about it talk you know brought it up and
that brought us in 200
every day of additional profit
wow by just raising the cost of a drink
by 50 cents yeah and
so like little keys can open up big
doors and and my coach buddy of mine his
name's daryl he uh you know he saved us
there got it
got us back to where we needed to be
so we have a lot of people that follow
me especially they listen to this
podcast who
um they're scared
they have beliefs that they've been
taught they don't want to be a bad
steward of the resources god's given
them they don't want to make unwise
decisions they know that time is
valuable they don't want to waste time
and and yet they
because of that they're sitting idle for
year after year after year burning with
these ideas not doing anything
yeah what would you say
as some wisdom to that person as
somebody who it sounds like
you've broken through that
yeah i think you know you have to take
action because
it's not just going to pop out of the
sky and your business is going to take
fire there's there's there's little
steps that you have to take one of the
things that
that really put me under the fire is
with uh and i know probably most people
watching aren't brick and mortar
businesses i'm sure some are but
uh with the brick and mortar business i
had a lease that i had signed i had the
city the county the health department uh
the building owner i had everybody and
the employees like jason you have to
open on june 1st like you have to and so
that put a fire in me uh to get that
done but but when i switched and i
started doing businesses like this
i realized um i could overthink things
and i could try to make i have to make
this perfect i have to do this and i
have to do that and and even a lot of
what you um have been sharing really
helps me because it was uh no you need
to take action and get revenue happening
now and i uh i've heard it said maybe it
was you that said that you know even
nike and and these major companies
that have been doing it for years they
still make mistakes and so
you just have to you have to take action
you have to road map out what you want
to do
and make goals that's what we're doing
now for one of the next businesses we're
working on or we're uh we're doing some
goals and my wife is actually the one
that's really helping me be accountable
and so that's awesome yeah yeah so i i
mean there's no
there's no cut course plan is as to how
to take action but you just have to what
feels right for you and just make some
smart goals and step out and and you
know again do it afraid because if we're
honest everybody's afraid to start
something new you don't know if it's
going to work out got a dream but but if
you don't step out you're never going to
know
what would you say to some people they
don't want to they don't want to ask
somebody who's been successful for help
because they're afraid of being a burden
and a bother to that person and they
think that well i i've asked people for
help and most people say no so i'm just
not going to ask again
yeah i would i would say for me that
that really hasn't been
my experience as far as as far as asking
for help so
i know if you people will think that
yeah so people fear rejection
um yeah
so sometimes they won't stop and ask or
maybe it's pride or maybe
you know there's all different reasons
why people won't ask but i remember uh
when i was on the other end of that
uh our juice bar we got a couple reward
or nominations or uh for best juice bar
in the northwest and we were in some
spoon magazine which was you know a
healthy eating thing and like this is
cool so we got a little bit of uh
attention on the media and somebody
called us up from a juice bar in another
state
asking
asking me some advice and i gave them
free advice i i talked to them and it
made me feel good because i'm like wait
somebody wants to hear what i've been
through and i was able to save them a
lot of pain and misery because there are
things that are specific to this
industry that i've been in for five
years and i could save them pain by okay
don't buy that piece of equipment
use this and and you'll see how things
will grow so i would say just ask just
just ask people if you get turned down
ask somebody again there's always
somebody that that will want to help you
because
you know it's a win-win situation um
you know people that are successful
love to help other people that are are
about to true it's absolutely true and
you're you're hearing watching this from
two people that have been there had to
ask for help have had success
ask don't be afraid a lot of people are
so afraid of getting turned down
uh here's the thing if somebody gets
rude or mean with you for asking for
help
they're uh
they're misrepresenting their success at
that point they're
they're probably insecure about their
success and they're trying to hide it
behind their anger
yeah
you know it's not like
you're not normally going to run into
that now
i'll say if you're going up to somebody
and saying hey i need you to buy this
and i need an investment from you
you got to be strategic as to the type
of help you ask so what would you say
like because if that guy said hey jason
i see you're so wealthy can you buy my
business and run it for me you'd
probably say click and hang up the phone
like but like and sometimes that's that
type of help that people need they don't
understand how to get capital or
whatever that is
but
they're not asking the right questions i
tell people you know the fact that
you're getting rejected is just it's the
wrong question and here's what i see
people do then they beat themselves up
for asking the wrong question they never
try to find out what the right questions
are because they feel embarrassed for
asking the wrong questions so once you
break past that embarrassment i've asked
a ton of really dumb questions before of
mentors and or the wrong people or
whatever but once you start doing it it
gets fun and exciting what are some of
the the strategic questions for example
the guy who came to you like how did he
approach you initially to ask how have
you approached mentors well uh the
people that approached me i i think they
were probably nervous too you know i got
this uh i got this message at our store
that some juice bar
uh
and i think it was idaho wanted to talk
to me and got on the phone and and it
was a lady and she was a new business
owner
and you know basically a lot of her
questions uh revolved around the process
uh as far as um working with employees
working with staff
advertising uh really the whole gamut of
everything
so so basically i just had a casual
conversation with her i said hey i'm not
an expert i have one store i'm not jamba
juice but this is how i did it these are
some of the mistakes i had made and
if if if any of this makes sense to you
that's great if it doesn't you can flush
it you know we're in different cities
different counties you know you can you
can take what what helps you and
and i think that that really empowered
her
and then made me feel good uh but as far
as
you know my businesses uh
i've i've asked people directly
uh for questions and help even even if
they're not in the same space as me
the business i'm working on now um
i'm asking people in the restaurant
industry some questions even though it's
not exactly
it's not a food business at all but
there is one piece of restaurant
equipment that we do use in the business
so i've already been asking about
commercial kitchen space and and really
just keep knocking is is what i would do
because like there's been many times i
asked somebody they're like oh i don't
know i have no idea and then i contacted
my buddy that that made cookies and i'm
like hey can you talk about these
massive
uh
like kitchenaid on steroids blenders
where do i get them do you know anybody
that's got used ones because that's one
of the things that we use
uh to make our next product and so
and i've asked a lot of stupid questions
before too and some of the input you get
might not be helpful but it's like
that one word that can unlock everything
or they might know somebody yeah that
that can just open up a brand new door
for you
so i don't know that really helps answer
it does help a lot kind of like kind of
like just fishing you know you just you
just try it and try and try and then
you'll have those connections where
you're really linked with somebody
and how do you do that and find time
with your family
and not neglect your family
i
i i put family first so family uh for me
is is the most important thing that's
why we why we do what we do
uh that's why
um even going forward we're trying to
create things that have more family time
or that we can all be
involved and so
uh either early in the morning or you
know my daughter's five right now so she
goes to bed about 7 30 or 8 so yeah i
can i can make phone calls and like i
was up until midnight last night working
on projects and so
uh i just try to be creative with my
time but then i don't beat myself up
because i know
there might be short seasons where
i might not be home to tuck in my
daughter every night because i got stuff
going on
but i always
make that the number one priority and i
talk to a lot of business owners where
they they're they're actually terrified
of
even having a night where they don't
tuck in their daughter like as if that
makes them a horrible
yeah parent or whatever
um or just that they just they don't see
literally
any possibility of even
one hour in their day
from morning to night
where they could ever do anything in a
business what how would you say that you
found your time and how did that
how did you develop that
yeah for me i just started to
schedule things that that worked with
our with our family went
that when i opened zoe juice bar um i
didn't have my daughter wasn't born
until 2017 and we opened in 2013 so
there's a big window where you know i
wasn't wasn't a parent and so
uh you know even when my daughter was
born um i just even things like i let
the store know you can't call me
all the time
uh was something that was really
important is i set up boundaries
and then i also set up systems so that
that my time
was my time and then what i tried to do
is uh set us like you can work in your
business and then you can work on your
business and so
a lot of the goal is to free yourself up
so you have have more time and so i
would set aside time i would set aside
time where i'm not in the business just
grinding away but that i would step back
and work maybe an hour a day on the
business on systems and things that
would ultimately
free up me and my family to do more
things that we love to do
um
but i i didn't have just a full
blueprint of of time with family but i
just i just made it a priority and the
other thing too is
is it sounded like what you're saying
this is a lot of people you said can
beat themselves up if they're not in
shame like
how they call it their obligations they
can't go out like that they're they're
non-negotiables that i'm with my family
24 7 at their beck and call and i
literally can't do anything
yeah i mean family is the most important
thing but again it can also
um
you have to you have to balance that
like you can't
i mean if you got a regular job you're
eight to five monday through friday or
your boss tells you to work overtime or
you gotta get i mean i have a lot of
friends that are flying all over the
country
and you know things come up you just
have to do the best you can but never
have shame there's like a few days that
goes by where you don't touch and
somebody i mean now with with social
media and
doom and facebook like we're more
connected than we ever have been yeah
and spoke so you could be on india on a
missions trip and not see your family
for a week but you can still connect
with them every single day
and so
i i think it's it's important to
you know not beat yourself up if there's
a little bit of time you miss and so you
do you you don't think that that
connecting with them digitally is
is destroying the family structure and
and
regressing back
uh or or being an unloving father
i mean if that's the only time you see
your family is through a stream
then
then then we might need to sit down and
have a talk
right if occasionally
you're on a business trip or traveling
or building an orphanage in uganda and
you're gone for a few weeks
this is like heaven like wow
i mean we've dreamed
we've dreamed of having this type of
technology
uh to communicate and see people and so
so yeah i mean
i think it's great
you said something powerful about
um
involving the family in it involving
them in the vision
yeah um
so like when you're
gone overseas
the family would you say that your
family is excited that you're gone
yes yeah definitely um i have now i
haven't went uh overseas since uh my
daughter's been born
but
um my wife and friends and other people
uh very very excited uh yeah
they feel part of that connection
because they're they're supporting with
you praying for you and and just
plus you know back when i first used to
travel
you know in 97 it was just an email that
you would send to somebody and now yeah
you can update your facebook from the
middle of the jungle and
people feel more connected to you
yeah that's true that's that's amazing
and so
there's so much opportunity out there
for people to
get into business
to
to learn from a mentor to be able to
learn what they don't know if they have
a vision
um
any i guess final thoughts on this as
far as i think this podcast is really
about you know how you practically take
a vision and make it happen
yeah any final thoughts on that for
people they have a vision for their life
they have a vision
um but they just they feel stuck and
some things that you wish that you knew
when you first got started
yeah i think a lot of it is mindset
um that that you really have to have you
know you can't have a positive life with
a negative mind and
these are the best days to be alive
the news social
media you know the economy all this
stuff going on um is fear fear fear fear
however
these are the best days to be alive and
the greatest opportunity for maximum
impact in whatever space you're in
whether it's coaching
training you know writing a book music
anything like with social media and the
way things accelerate tick tock you name
it
there is such an opportunity to reach
large audiences
really from your home
and
this is a great opportunity for people
and the people that are walking in doubt
and fear and unbelief and
i mean i have people that i know that
are i'm not gonna i'm not gonna make any
decisions till the next election or i'm
not gonna do anything until until this
happens well
you're missing out because there's a
momentum that can happen fast when you
begin to to step into your calling and
your gifting yeah and you know it's for
me wow i just had to do it afraid like
very afraid many times and
you can't let that stop you and so
whatever vision you have whatever
passion you have that that's inside of
you
you know now is the time to start now is
the time to get involved and just take
just take steps i
one last thing i was thinking about is
um
you know everybody's looking for a sign
or something to fly in the sky or
whatever and and
you know i i've had friends that you
know i want to start a coffee shop well
what are you doing i don't know i just
drink coffee but but what are you doing
to start your coffee shop and and
instead
you know
start to start to look at coffee shops
what they're doing how they're doing it
starting a little bit or a book or a
course
uh and and then just take those small
steps yeah
that's amazing that's incredible you
know i i have a big vision
to
create video games and i so i broke down
and like okay what are the steps of this
okay we got programming we got art we
have 3d design we have storytelling we
have game structure um i'm not very good
at all of those except for maybe
storytelling
and so i was like okay what's the
fastest way for me to get better at
storytelling and i've dove into that and
i was like okay study comic books and i
was like okay
novels like writing novels and i've been
studying story structure because i see
that as
the gateway that's going to kind of get
me into that because it's already using
gifts and talents that i have
yeah another retelling that's awesome
and just you sharing that uh a friend of
mine that i
excuse me that i did missions with
um
my buddy his wife uh became so
successful in her business
that he actually left his full-time
business to make video games oh wow
that's awesome yeah so i can i can share
more offline but yeah yeah great that's
so cool that you're going for that
yeah i um again i'm like i know that the
business that i'm supposed to build
right now is in this space
um but like long-term vision
um and then i realized okay i'm probably
gonna need some investors so i've been
connecting with different
people that do
roll ups and venture capital and things
like that just to build relationships
with them so yeah
you know another quick thing too that
somebody spoke me spoke to me that
really helped me out is i was stuck as
far as
i was doing water bottles
and i was really focused on that and a
friend of mine met with me and i was
talking about water bottles and
basically he's like bro jason
you can do
more than one thing at a time you know
this is not taking up 40 50 60 hours of
your week even though
maybe in your mind it is once it's
systematized it doesn't have to yeah
exactly and he's like jason i can see
you doing this you can do this and you
can do this
and a few other things like you know you
look at elon musk and different people
they run you know people that run huge
companies several of them
and so that that really freed me up to
to start doing other things and so
you know people that are watching right
now you're like well i'm working a
full-time job or i have this happening
well if you really prioritize and get
your mind in the right place and your
actions right place you'll be surprised
at what you can accomplish and so i for
me personally i stepped out in that and
so now i got my hands in a few different
things and and it's awesome you know you
just it's just enjoyable
that's great that's wonderful i i
absolutely love that
um
did you find i guess i have another like
kind of question i want to ask you
before we close here i know we were
going to close up but we could just keep
talking a little bit so my
journey
every level that i go to
is uh and sometimes i i ask questions of
people when i have them on the podcast
like i want to know for myself
um i found that i have to say no to the
good to get to the great
yeah no to the good ideas no to the you
know a couple clients we've had to say
okay we can't serve you at the same
level i'm gonna have to say no to the
obligation
and restructure our contract to be able
to build this calling that i have
yeah so what would have you experienced
that and and
any wisdom in that area yeah i think
i think i had to
uh really a little bit to what you're
saying is i had to really focus in into
what i was doing and i think you said it
you know sometimes
good is the enemy of best and
and there were some there's some doors
that will open for you that you're not
supposed to go into
yeah there's things that'll uh come in
front of you but but really it's it's a
distraction
from
and so
but i've made sometimes
i've made mistakes as far as
uh there's been something i knew i
needed to change
yeah because i want to hurt somebody or
i didn't want to let somebody down i
just went through this recently with a
with a nonprofit that i was involved
with it's like i'll stay in sometimes we
can stay in something when the grace is
gone um yeah and and it's important to
to really try to take action and and
pivot quickly and it's almost like you
know you just rip the band-aid off and
it hurts for a minute
and then
you know when i when i made the
transition recently with
the thing i was talking about with the
non-profit doors begin to open up as as
i shut as i shut another door yeah and
so yeah i think
there's a lot of
a lot of room to and and it's almost
like
i think we get so rigid
that
that we've got this vision
and idea that we want to accomplish
so we hit on our gps okay this is where
i'm going this is my destination
and then it doesn't work out and we take
a side road and we freak out but the
nice thing about gps navigation is you
turn the wrong way
it just says
back it says rerouting you can turn you
can turn the wrong way for a week and
that gps is still going to tell you
this is the way you go yep and so
yeah i think with all that with you know
changing contracts and telling clients
you know hey this might not work
it all serves the purpose that the
attempt you know
that you have for your life
or or some people have to say it to
people at church or their family or
and i like i'm not like in the home
immediate family necessarily but even
sometimes i have to say like no i can't
do that right now but i can do that
tomorrow yeah not always giving people
what they want to build your life and
and
i feel like we're taught that that's
selfish when in fact it's the most
selfless thing we can do
yeah
yeah one thing i learned and i really
learned it a lot from my wife she's been
very strong for me in this season
because you know these last three years
have been challenging for me um
hasn't all been roses but i i get up and
i go and i go but uh what i what she
would tell me she didn't say these words
but i've heard this like an emergency on
your part doesn't constitute an
emergency on my part and a lot of times
like you said church but it could be
business
somebody might call you
and they think the world is falling
apart and they want to call back
immediately
usually if you give them 24 hours
whatever emergency they had yeah he
worked out on his own yep yeah now
obviously with family and different
things you know we want to be really
accessible but you don't just want to be
accessible
to the entire planet or your entire team
right
20 24 7.
right and it's it's that's so important
is to learn to have those boundaries to
learn that people get different levels
of access
um thank you for being on here this has
been
incredible i i think this is a lot of
value for people
um i love the points that you
had i'm going to listen to this again as
well
yeah where can people find you
um online
well we've got uh we've got a couple
things going um revivaltown.com is is
our ministry uh website
and then
that the next thing that we we started
is a is a kid's slime business so we
have
shaka slime
calm
nice yeah
yeah that's awesome yeah well that's
exciting um
shaka slime he's like this little
pineapple guy exactly yeah
that's awesome yeah so we're making
healthy healthy slime for kids and
putting in essential oils instead of uh
you know fragrance that
most companies use to have you know
oil-based and
won't go into that whole thing but
naturals always better
that's really fun that's really exciting
i'm gonna have to share this with um
with uh with my wife and with my mom too
this is cool
yeah all right well i'm excited i think
this will be a fun business for you
yeah and again like i said uh whole
family's involved so it's it's like my
you know my wife and daughter basically
the ones steering it i'm just helping
out with yeah the other things but yeah
family stuff
awesome well hey everybody listen if
this podcast has helped you
make sure that you share it with
somebody don't keep this information to
yourself that's how the podcast grows
and by sharing it with other people and
so you can be a part of getting this
message out encourage encouraging
somebody to take risks to go after their
vision and to to do the big hairy
audacious things
that are inside of them instead of
letting fear be the master and commander
of your life you can go after your life
and create it and ultimately fulfill the
calling and the purpose that god has put
on your life
thank you jason for being here yeah
thank you pleasure
everybody grow your life we'll talk soon
have a good one
all right
that was good that was